<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>EPLAN</title>
 <link href="https://sstasl.github.io/eplan/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://sstasl.github.io/eplan/"/>
 <updated>2016-06-02T22:32:29+03:00</updated>
 <id>https://sstasl.github.io/eplan</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Introducing BlackDoc</title>
   <link href="https://sstasl.github.io/eplan/2016/06/02/first/"/>
   <updated>2016-06-02T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
   <id>https://sstasl.github.io/eplan/2016/06/02/first</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;first post&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introducing BlackDoc</title>
   <link href="https://sstasl.github.io/eplan/2015/05/14/introducing-blackdoc/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-14T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
   <id>https://sstasl.github.io/eplan/2015/05/14/introducing-blackdoc</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;BlackDoc is a two-column &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; theme that&amp;#39;s ideal for websites that require a master-detail layout for viewing of content. It&amp;#39;s based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpoole.com&quot;&gt;Poole&lt;/a&gt;, the Jekyll butler, and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hyde.getpoole.com&quot;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt; theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed a two-column layout with a scrolling sidebar to publish my &lt;a href=&quot;http://karloespiritu.com/cheatsheets&quot;&gt;code cheatsheets&lt;/a&gt;, and found the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hyde.getpoole.com&quot;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt; Jekyll theme to be a good starting theme. To complement the color scheme of my main &lt;a href=&quot;http://karloespiritu.com&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, I customised the theme to make it look great in black background and changed the sidebar to display scrolling content. I created this theme because I can&amp;#39;t seem to find any good Jekyll theme with a master-detail layout. Hopefully, someone will find this useful as well in their own projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Built on Poole&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poole is the Jekyll Butler, serving as a foundation for creating Jekyll themes. Poole-based themes, such as BlackDoc here, include the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete Jekyll setup included (layouts, config, &lt;a href=&quot;/404&quot;&gt;404&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/atom.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;, posts, and &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;example page&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly design and development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily scalable text and component sizing with &lt;code&gt;rem&lt;/code&gt; units in the CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for a wide gamut of HTML elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Related posts (time-based, because Jekyll) below each post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syntax highlighting using Pygments (the Python-based code snippet highlighter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;BlackDoc Features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the features of &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpoole.com&quot;&gt;Poole&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://hyde.getpoole.com&quot;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt;, BlackDoc theme adds the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scrolling sidebar with a thin scrollbar to allow displaying of numerous top-level content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elements and classes of the Hyde theme were updated to look great in black background. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;styles&quot;&gt;Theme Styles&lt;/a&gt; to see the stylings used in the theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;code&gt;Readme&lt;/code&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/poole&quot;&gt;Poole&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/hyde&quot;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt; theme to learn more about the features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Browser support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BlackDoc theme supports most modern browsers and only compatible with Internet Explorer 9 and above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Download&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BlackDoc is a free Jekyll theme and hosted with GitHub. Head to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/karloespiritu/BlackDoc&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; to download.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What's Jekyll?</title>
   <link href="https://sstasl.github.io/eplan/2012/02/06/whats-jekyll/"/>
   <updated>2012-02-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>https://sstasl.github.io/eplan/2012/02/06/whats-jekyll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is a static site generator, an open-source tool for creating simple yet powerful websites of all shapes and sizes. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/blob/master/README.markdown&quot;&gt;the project&amp;#39;s readme&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a simple, blog aware, static site generator. It takes a template directory [...] and spits out a complete, static website suitable for serving with Apache or your favorite web server. This is also the engine behind GitHub Pages, which you can use to host your project’s page or blog right here from GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out more by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;visiting the project on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
